[    
    {
    "question": "Who was the Man of the Series in the test series played between India and England recently in 2024?",
    "options": ["R Ashwin", "Rohit Sharma", "Yashaswi Jaiswal", "Shubman Gill"],
    "answer": "Yashaswi Jaiswal"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who holds the record for the highest individual score in Test cricket?",
    "options": ["Sachin Tendulkar", "Brian Lara", "Ricky Ponting", "Virat Kohli"],
    "answer": "Brian Lara"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which country is known for the famous cricketing venue, the Gabba?",
    "options": ["England", "Australia", "South Africa", "West Indies"],
    "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who was the first cricketer to score a double century in ODIs?",
    "options": ["Virender Sehwag", "Sachin Tendulkar", "Chris Gayle", "Rohit Sharma"],
    "answer": "Sachin Tendulkar"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which batter holds the record for most sixes in international cricket?",
    "options": ["Chris Gayle", "Rohit Sharma", "Shahid Afridi", "AB de Villiers"],
    "answer": "Rohit Sharma"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which bowler is the leading wicket-taker in Test cricket?",
    "options": ["Muralitharan", "Shane Warne", "James Anderson", "Anil Kumble"],
    "answer": "Muralitharan"
    },
    {
    "question": "When was the first-ever Cricket World Cup played?",
    "options": ["1952", "1975", "1979", "1962"],
    "answer": "1975"
    },
    {
    "question": "Among the following actors, which actor is commonly recognized as the 'Angry Young Man'?",
    "options": ["Shah Rukh Khan", "Saif Ali Khan", "John Abrahim", "Amitabh Bachchan"],
    "answer": "Amitabh Bachchan"
    },
    {
    "question": "The film industry of India is mottled for its underworld acquaintances. Among the following people, who was killed by the underworld thugs?",
    "options": ["Sanjeev Kumar", "Divya Bharti", "Gulshan Kumar", "Vinod Mehra"],
    "answer": "Gulshan Kumar"
    },
    {
    "question": "This movie was based on a Cricket match and was admired by people all around the world. It was nominated as the Best Foreign Film at Oscars in the year 2001. Identify the movie.",
    "options": ["Refugee", "Mohabbatein", "Badal", "Lagaan"],
    "answer": "Lagaan"
    },
    {
    "question": "Among the following actresses, the Lux New Face award of the year 1997 was bagged by?",
    "options": ["Aishwarya Rai", "Mahima Chowdhary", "Rani Mukherjee", "Sushmita Sen"],
    "answer": "Mahima Chowdhary"
    },
    {
    "question": "The songs of Raj Kapoor’s movie were always a super hit. One of the blockbuster Raj Kapoor films was the movie 'Bobby'. Can you identify the music director of this film?",
    "options": ["Adnan Sami", "Anand Raj Anand", "Anil Biswas", "Laxmikant-Pyarelal"],
    "answer": "Laxmikant-Pyarelal"
    },
    {
    "question": "One of the greatest movies of Bollywood is 'Mughal-E-Azam'. Can you name the music director of this movie?",
    "options": ["Arjun Janya", "Anoop Seelin", "Naushad Ali", "G. Devarajan"],
    "answer": "Naushad Ali"
    },
    {
    "question": "The story of the movie ‘Hello’, directed by Atul Agnihotri, was adapted from which famed novel?",
    "options": ["One Night at the Call Center", "The God of Small Things", "The White Tiger", "Midnight’s Children"],
    "answer": "One Night at the Call Center"
    },
    {
    "question": " Itna sannata kyun hai bhai? is a very famous dialogue. Who said these famous words in the movie Sholay?",
    "options": ["Dharmendra", "Sanjeev Kumar", "Amjad Khan", "A. K. Hangal"],
    "answer": "A. K. Hangal"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which is India's first indigenously made Colour film?",
    "options": ["Bachpan", "Baarish", "Kisan Kanya", "Badshah"],
    "answer": "Kisan Kanya"
    },
    {
    "question": "This Bollywood star was chosen as one of the jury members for the Cannes Film Festival in 2003?",
    "options": ["Aishwarya Rai", "Salman Khan", "Juhi Chawla", "Sushmita Sen"],
    "answer": "Aishwarya Rai"
    },

    {
    "question": "Who plays the character of blind companion in the movie Dosti released in 1964?",
    "options": ["Ramu", "Shamu", "Deepu", "Mohan"],
    "answer": "Mohan"
    },
    {
    "question": "Among the following personalities, who is commonly recognized as the 'Father of Indian Cinema'?",
    "options": ["Shatrughan Sinha", "Yash Chopra", "Dadasaheb Phalke", "Priyadarshan"],
    "answer": "Dadasaheb Phalke"
    },
    {
    "question": "Among the following movies, which one is not directed by Mr. V. Shantaram?",
    "options": ["Stree", "Razia Sultan", "Geet Gaya Patharon Ne", "Amar Bhoopali"],
    "answer": "Razia Sultan"
    },
    {
    "question": "She made her debut film along with the renowned actor Raj Kapoor with the movie 'Neel Kamal'?",
    "options": ["Aamani", "Anita Raj", "Bindu", "Madhubala"],
    "answer": "Madhubala"
    },
    {
    "question": "The famous Music Director R.D. Burman is also recognized as?",
    "options": ["Pancham", "Shera", "Veeru", "Neel"],
    "answer": "Pancham"
    },
    {
    "question": "This Indian actor is recognized as the 'Tragedy King'. Identify him.",
    "options": ["Anupam Kher", "A.K. Hangal", "Dilip Kumar", "Prem Chopra"],
    "answer": "Dilip Kumar"
    },
    {
    "question": "Madhubala, the gorgeous Bollywood actress was married to?",
    "options": ["Kishore Kumar", "Dilip Kumar", "Ashok Kumar", "Prem Chopra"],
    "answer": "Kishore Kumar"
    },
    {
    "question": "This actor’s real name was Shivaji Rao Gaikwad. Identify him.",
    "options": ["Abhishek Bachhan", "Rajnikant", "Kamal Hassan", "Prakash Raj"],
    "answer": "Rajnikant"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which is the first narrative feature film in India?",
    "options": ["Pundalik", "Raja Harishchandra", "Alam Ara", "Sant Tukaram"],
    "answer": "Pundalik"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which is the first indigenous feature film in India?",
    "options": ["Pundalik", "Alam Ara", "Sant Tukaram", "Raja Harishchandra"],
    "answer": "Raja Harishchandra"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which is the first talkie film in India?",
    "options": ["Pundalik", "Alam Ara", "Sant Tukaram", "Raja Harishchandra"],
    "answer": "Alam Ara"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which is the first golden jubilee film of India?",
    "options": ["Pundalik", "Alam Ara", "Sant Tukaram", "Raja Harishchandra"],
    "answer": "Sant Tukaram"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which is the first Sanskrit film?",
    "options": ["Shankaracharya", "Bhagavad Gita", "Gunda", "Margazhi Raagam"],
    "answer": "Shankaracharya"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which is the first telefilm of India?",
    "options": ["Sadgati", "Pather Panchali", "Pikoo", "Bala"],
    "answer": "Sadgati"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which is the first serialised animation film in India?",
    "options": ["Ek Anek aur ekta", "Ghayab Aya", "Kittu", "Motu Patlu"],
    "answer": "Ghayab Aya"
    },

    {
    "question": "Who among the following invented the cinematograph?",
    "options": ["Lumiere Brothers", "Mani Sethna", "Dada Saheb Phalke", "Dhirendra Nath Ganguly"],
    "answer": "Lumiere Brothers"
    },
    {
    "question": "Where was the first cinema demonstrated in India?",
    "options": ["Hindi Theatre at Kolkata", "Bombay (Now Mumbai) at Watkins Hotel", "Athenaeeum and Chaurang Theatre", "Laffed Faire"],
    "answer": "Bombay (Now Mumbai) at Watkins Hotel"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who among the following made first Film Theatre of India?",
    "options": ["Lumiere Brothers", "Mani Sethna", "Dada Saheb Phalke", "Dhirendra Nath Ganguly"],
    "answer": "Mani Sethna"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which of the following the first foreign film was demonstrated in India?",
    "options": ["Magic Lamp", "Arrival of the train", "Life of Christ", "Sea Birth"],
    "answer": "Life of Christ"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who among the following made the first fully indigenous silent feature film in India?",
    "options": ["Lumiere Brothers", "Mani Sethna", "Dada Saheb Phalke", "Dhirendra Nath Ganguly"],
    "answer": "Dada Saheb Phalke"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who among the following was the first Indian woman producer and director in Indian cinema?",
    "options": ["Fatima Begum", "WM Khan", "Alam Ara", "Ardeshir Irani"],
    "answer": "Fatima Begum"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which was the first India's talkie film?",
    "options": ["Alam Ara", "Pundlik", "Raja Harishchandra", "Nal Damayanti"],
    "answer": "Alam Ara"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who among the following is known as 'Father of Indian Cinema'?",
    "options": ["Dhundhi Raj Govind Phalke", "Dada Sheb Phalke", "Both A and B", "Mani Sethna"],
    "answer": "Both A and B"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which of the following regional cinema referred to as Kollywood?",
    "options": ["Punjabi Cinema", "Tamil Cinema", "Marathi Cinema", "Malayalam Cinema"],
    "answer": "Tamil Cinema"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which of the following was the first made indigenous, coloured film of India?",
    "options": ["Alama Ara", "Pather Panchali", "Kisan Kanya", "Devdas"],
    "answer": "Kisan Kanya"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which was the first Indian movie nominated for Oscar?",
    "options": ["Mother India", "Salaam Bombay", "Lagaan", "Mr. India"],
    "answer": "Mother India"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which was the first Indian movie to win an Oscar?",
    "options": ["Mother India", "Lagaan", "Gandhi", "Slumdog Millionaire"],
    "answer": "Gandhi"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who got first Oscar award in India?",
    "options": ["AR Rahman", "Bhanu Athaiya", "Anil Kapoor", "Sri Devi"],
    "answer": "Bhanu Athaiya"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who is known as the Father of Indian cinema?",
    "options": ["Raja Lalith Rai", "Balram Naidu", "Charan Singh", "Dhundiraj Govind Phalke"],
    "answer": "Dhundiraj Govind Phalke"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which is the highest grossing Indian film ever?",
    "options": ["Dangal", "Bajrangi Bhaijaan", "PK", "Sultan"],
    "answer": "Dangal"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which actor has won the most national awards in India?",
    "options": ["Amitabh Bachchan", "Salman Khan", "Aamir Khan", "Shah Rukh Khan"],
    "answer":  "Shah Rukh Khan"
    },

    {
    "question": "Which Hindi movie got first National Award?",
    "options":["Jagriti", "Mirza Ghalib", "Tezab", "Shree 420"],
    "answer":  "Mirza Ghalib"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which was the first film to win the Filmfare Best Film Award?",
    "options": ["Chandani", "Jagriti", "Boot Polish", "Do Bigha Zamin"],
    "answer": "Do Bigha Zamin"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who was the director of the famous movie ‘Sholay’?",
    "options": ["Ramesh Sippy", "Mehboob Khan", "G. P. Sippy", "Shakti Samanta"],
    "answer":  "Ramesh Sippy"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which was the first Cinemascope film in Bollywood?",
    "options": ["Sholay", "Lok Parlok", "Kaagaz Ke Phool", "Naya Daur"],
    "answer":  "Kaagaz Ke Phool"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who was known as first lady of Indian cinema?",
    "options": ["Sri Devi", "Devika Rani Chaudhuri", "Suraiya", "Meena Kumari"],
    "answer":  "Devika Rani Chaudhuri"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who was the first Indian actress to receive the Padma Shri award?",
    "options": ["Madhuri Dixit", "Nargis Dutt", "Bhanumathi Ramakrishna", "Meena Kumari"],
    "answer":  "Nargis Dutt"
    },
    {
    "question": "The first ever Indian film that got popularity outside India was ‘Awara’. The hero in that film was a famous actor, also known as the Show Man. This person was the son of Prithviraj Kapoor. Who was he?",
    "options": ["Raj Kapoor", "Randhir Kapoor", "Ranbir Kapoor", "Rishi Kapoor"],
    "answer":  "Raj Kapoor"
    },
    {
    "question": "In 1957-58, India, for the first time, sent a film for the Best Foreign Film Award at the Academy Awards. This film, directed by Mehboob Khan, made the shortlist. Name this legendary Hindi epic film.",
    "options": ["Mirza Ghalib", "Salaam Bombay", "Mother India", "Mughal-e-Azam"],
    "answer":  "Mother India"
    },
    {
    "question": "In 1988, a film called ‘Salaam Bombay’ was released. This film, depicting the daily life of street children in Mumbai, was very famous. By whom was it directed?",
    "options": ["Rituparno Ghosh", "Mehboob Khan", "Mansoor Khan", "Mira Nair"],
    "answer":  "Mira Nair"
    },
    {
    "question": "In 2001, an epic sports film starring Aamir Khan was released. The tagline of this film was ‘Once Upon A Time in India’. It was the third Indian film to make the shortlist of the best Foreign Film Oscar. Name this film which is based in Champaner in modern-day Gujarat.",
    "options": ["Ghajini", "Lagaan", "Don", "The Good Road"],
    "answer":  "Lagaan"
    },
    {
    "question": "The film ‘3 idiots’ was the first Indian film to gross more than Rupees 200 crore (or 2 billion) in India. Who starred as the hero in this film, directed by Rajkumar Hirani?",
    "options": ["Ranvir Singh", "Hrithik Roshan", "Aamir Khan", "Ranbir Kapoor"],
    "answer":  "Aamir Khan"
    },
    {
    "question": "The 1st Sanskrit Film of India was?",
    "options": ["Mudrarakshasam", "Satyawadi Raja Harishchandra", "Bharati Balak", "Adi Shankaracharya"],
    "answer": "Adi Shankaracharya"
    },
    {
    "question": "The 1st fully indigenously made India’s silent feature film was?",
    "options": ["Achhut Kanya", "Zarina", "Raja Harishchandra", "Jeevan Naiya"],
    "answer": "Raja Harishchandra"
    },
    {
    "question": "The 1st English film of India was?",
    "options": ["The Darjeeling Limited", "Court Dancer", "The Best Exotic Marigold Hotel", "The Namesake"],
    "answer": "Court Dancer"
    },
    {
    "question": "The 1st film festival of India was held at?",
    "options": ["Mumbai", "Delhi", "Chennai", "Lucknow"],
    "answer" : "Mumbai"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which was the first 3D movie in India?",
    "options": ["Roadside Romeo", "Chhota Chetan", "Laila Majnu", "My Dear Kuttichathan"],
    "answer": "My Dear Kuttichathan"
    },

    {
    "question": "Who is the music director for the Movie Missamma (Bhoomika's)?",
    "options": ["Keeravani", "Manisharma", "R.P. Patnaik", "Vandemataram Srinivas"],
    "answer": "Vandemataram Srinivas"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who is the hero that played Venkatesh's brother role in the movie Sankranthi?",
    "options": ["Raviteja", "Srikanth", "Yoganand", "None of the above"],
    "answer": "Srikanth"
    },
    {
    "question": "What is Suddhardh's last movie till today? (released movie)",
    "options": ["Nuvvostaanante Nenoddantaana", "Chukkalo Chandrudu", "Aata", "Konchan Ishtam Koncham Kashtam"],
    "answer": "Aata"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who is the director of the movie Jalsa?",
    "options": ["Srinu Vaitla", "Trivikram", "V.V. Vinayak", "Bhaskar"],
    "answer": "Trivikram"
    },
    {
    "question": "What is Brahmanandam's character name in the movie Ready?",
    "options": ["Mc Dowell Murthy", "Ms Donald Murthy", "MC Donal Murthy", "MC Donald Murthy"],
    "answer": "Mc Dowell Murthy"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which is Megastar's last Movie?",
    "options": ["Andarivaadu", "Shankardada Zindabad", "Stalin", "Shankardada M.B.B.S."],
    "answer": "Shankardada Zindabad"
    },
    {
    "question": "How many characters did Nagarjuna perform in his latest flick, KING?",
    "options": ["3", "2", "1", "4"],
    "answer": "3"
    },
    {
    "question": "With how many heroines did Nag Danced in his special song in the Movie KING?",
    "options": ["6", "10", "8", "2"],
    "answer": "8"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who is the singer sang the song 'Pillagali Allari' in the movie ATHADU?",
    "options": ["Sunitha", "Usha", "Kousalya", "Shreya Ghoshal"],
    "answer": "Shreya Ghoshal"
    },
    {
    "question": "Among which of the hero's Trisha did not act with?",
    "options": ["Chiranjeevi", "Venkatesh", "Tarun", "None of the above"],
    "answer": "None of the above"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which 1985 film had the tagline “He’s the only kid ever to get into trouble before he was born”?",
    "options": ["The Breakfast Club", "Back to the Future", "The Colour Purple", "The Clue"],
    "answer": "Back to the Future"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which 1959 film won 11 Oscars?",
    "options": ["Room at the Top", "The Diary of Anne Frank", "Ben Hur", "Anatomy of a Murder"],
    "answer": "Ben Hur"
    },
    {
    "question": "In which James Bond film was there the following exchange: “You expect me to talk?” “No, Mr Bond, I expect you to die!”?",
    "options": ["Live and Let die", "A view to a kill", "Thunderball", "Goldfinger"],
    "answer": "Goldfinger"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who won the Oscars 2012 for the Actor in a Leading role?",
    "options": ["George Clooney", "Gary Oldman", "Demian Bichir", "Jean Dujardin"],
    "answer": "Jean Dujardin"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which film won the Oscars 2012 for the Best Animated Feature Film?",
    "options": ["Kung Fu Panda 2", "Puss in Boots", "Rango", "Chiko and Rita"],
    "answer": "Rango"
    },
    {
    "question": "National Film Awards 2012 were the",
    "options": ["57th", "58th", "59th", "60th"],
    "answer": "59th"
    },
    {
    "question": "The National Awards 2012 for Best dialogues was awarded to",
    "options": ["Javed Akhtar", "Girish Kulkarni"],
    "answer": "Girish Kulkarni"
    },
    {
    "question": "In which year was the best foreign film category introduced to the Academy Awards?",
    "options": ["1946", "1948", "1956", "1958"],
    "answer": "1948"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which is the only Disney Movie to be nominated for 13 Academy Awards?",
    "options": ["Mary Janes", "Mary Poppins", "Alladin", "Little Mermaid"],
    "answer": "Mary Poppins"
    },
    {
    "question": "When did the film industry start to have a big effect?",
    "options": ["Early 20th Century", "Early 15th Century", "Early 19th Century", "Early 1st Century"],
    "answer": "Early 20th Century"
    },
    {
    "question": "What was the dominant style in American Cinema?",
    "options": ["Classic Cinema", "Western Cinema", "The Star Cinema", "Romantic Comedy"],
    "answer": "Classic Cinema"
    },
    {
    "question": "What was the style attributed to the French Auguste and Louis Lumière?",
    "options": ["Modern Cinema", "Animated Cinema", "Action Cinema", "Actuality Film"],
    "answer": "Modern Cinema"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who is considered the father of animation?",
    "options": ["Winsor McCay", "Hanna Barbera", "Warner Brothers", "Walt Disney"],
    "answer": "Winsor McCay"
    },
    {
    "question": "What was the first Computer-animated movie?",
    "options": ["Mickey Mouse", "Toy Story", "The Lion King", "Fantasia"],
    "answer": "Toy Story"
    },
    {
    "question": "Since what year has computer animation been around?",
    "options": ["Over two hundred years", "Over a Hundred years", "Since 80 years","Since 50 years"],
    "answer": "Over a Hundred years"
    },
    {
    "question": "In what year was the animation Gertie the Dinosaur shown to the public?",
    "options": ["1998", "1965", "1980", "1914"],
    "answer": "1914"
    },

    {
    "question": "Who was Charlie Chaplin?",
    "options": ["An artist", "A singer", "A poet", "An actor"],
    "answer": "An actor"
    },
    {
    "question": "How Hollywood is considered?",
    "options": ["The oldest film industry", "A tourist place", "The newest film industry", "A museum"],
    "answer": "The oldest film industry"
    },
    {
    "question": "In what year did American cinema classify Hollywood?",
    "options": ["Between 1958 and 1980", "Between 1913 and 1969", "Between 1952 and 1954", "Between 1942 and 1969"],
    "answer": "Between 1913 and 1969"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who among the following was the first Indian cricketer to score 100 runs in his 100th ODI match?",
    "options": ["Sachin Tendulkar", "Virat Kohli", "Rohit Sharma", "Shikhar Dhawan"],
    "answer": "Shikhar Dhawan"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who among the following has scored the first double century in World Cup Cricket?",
    "options": ["Sachin Tendulkar", "Ricky Ponting", "AB de Villiers", "Chris Gayle"],
    "answer": "Chris Gayle"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who was the first Bangladeshi cricketer to score a double century in test cricket?",
    "options": ["Shakib Al Hasan", "Mushfiqur Rahim", "Tamim Iqbal", "Mahmudullah"],
    "answer": "Mushfiqur Rahim"
    },
    {
    "question": "What was the name of the Cricket World Cup played in 1987?",
    "options": ["Benson & Hedges World Cup", "Reliance Cup", "Prudential World Cup", "ICC Cricket World Cup"],
    "answer": "Reliance Cup"
    },
    {
    "question": "In which year was Sachin Tendulkar given the Arjuna Award?",
    "options": ["1990", "1992", "1994", "1996"],
    "answer": "1994"
    },
    {
    "question": "The Brabourne Cricket Stadium is situated in which Indian state?",
    "options": ["Karnataka", "Maharashtra", "Tamil Nadu", "West Bengal"],
    "answer": "Maharashtra"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who was the first Indian woman cricketer honored with MCC life membership?",
    "options": ["Jhulan Goswami", "Mithali Raj", "Anjum Chopra", "Harmanpreet Kaur"],
    "answer": "Anjum Chopra"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which of the following is the first woman cricketer who scored 6000 runs in ODIs?",
    "options": ["Mithali Raj", "Jhulan Goswami", "Smriti Mandhana", "Harmanpreet Kaur"],
    "answer": "Mithali Raj"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which Indian batsman was the first to hit six consecutive sixes in first-class cricket?",
    "options": ["Sunil Gavaskar", "Ravi Shastri", "Sachin Tendulkar", "Kapil Dev"],
    "answer": "Ravi Shastri"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who has become the first bowler in the world to claim five international hat-tricks?",
    "options": ["Wasim Akram (Pakistan)", "Glenn McGrath (Australia)", "Lasith Malinga (Sri Lanka)", "Shane Warne (Australia)"],
    "answer": "Lasith Malinga (Sri Lanka)"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who was the first sportsperson nominated for Rajya Sabha membership?",
    "options": ["Sachin Tendulkar", "Mary Kom", "Kapil Dev", "Milkha Singh"],
    "answer": "Sachin Tendulkar"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who holds the world record of the highest number of consecutive maiden overs in a test match?",
    "options": ["Bishan Singh Bedi", "Kapil Dev", "Anil Kumble", "Bapu Nadkarni"],
    "answer": "Bapu Nadkarni"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who was the highest run-scorer from India in the World Cup Cricket final match, 1983?",
    "options": ["Kapil Dev", "Sunil Gavaskar", "Mohinder Amarnath", "K Srikkanth"],
    "answer": "K Srikkanth"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who became the first cricketer to win three top ICC honors in the same year?",
    "options": ["Sachin Tendulkar", "Ricky Ponting", "Virat Kohli", "MS Dhoni"],
    "answer": "Virat Kohli"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which Indian Cricketer became the fastest batsman in the world to reach the 20,000 international runs mark?",
    "options": ["Sachin Tendulkar", "Virat Kohli", "Rohit Sharma", "MS Dhoni"],
    "answer": "Virat Kohli"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who took the most wickets in ICC Men’s World Cup 2023?",
    "options": ["Virat Kohli", "Mohammed Shami", "Rohit Sharma", "Jasprit Bumrah"],
    "answer": "Mohammed Shami"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who was the runner-up in ICC Men’s ODI World Cup 2023?",
    "options": ["Australia", "England", "India", "New Zealand"],
    "answer": "India"
    },
    {
    "question": "What is the date of ICC Men’s ODI World Cup 2023?",
    "options": ["From 1 January to 30 January 2023", "From 15 March to 10 April 2023", "From 5 October to 19 November 2023", "From 20 June to 5 July 2023"],
    "answer": "From 5 October to 19 November 2023"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which bowler holds the record for the most wickets taken in Test cricket history?",
    "options": ["Shane Warne (Australia)", "Glenn McGrath (Australia)", "Muttiah Muralitharan (Sri Lanka)", "James Anderson (England)"],
    "answer": "Muttiah Muralitharan"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who has written the Biography of Mohammed Azharuddin, 'Azhar'?",
    "options": ["Azharuudin", "Harsha Bhogle", "Harbhajan Singh", "Azhar’s Mother"],
    "answer": "Harsha Bhogle"
    },
    {
    "question": "India played its first one day in ?",
    "options": ["1970", "1971", "1972", "1974"],
    "answer": "1974"
    },
    {
    "question": "Yuvraj Singh scored his first one-day century against—",
    "options": ["Bangladesh", "Sri Lanka", "Australia", "New Zealand"],
    "answer": "Bangladesh"
    },
    {
    "question": "Sachin Tendulkar played his One-day debut against",
    "options": ["India", "Australia", "Pakistan", "Sri Lanka"],
    "answer": "Pakistan"
    },
    {
    "question": "Sunil Gavaskar scored his first one day century against—",
    "options": ["Pakistan", "England", "West Indies", "New Zealand"],
    "answer": "New Zealand"
    },
    {
    "question": "India Played its first one-day international match at home in—",
    "options": ["1981 at Ahmedabad", "1981 at Calcutta", "1982 at Chennai", "1981 at Chennai"],
    "answer": "1981 at Ahmedabad"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who was India’s first One-day captain.",
    "options": ["Sunil Gavaskar", "Kapil dev", "Manoj prabhakar", "Ajit Wadekar"],
    "answer": "Ajit Wadekar"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who holds the record for the fastest IPL century?",
    "options": ["Virat Kohli", "Rohit Sharma", "AB de Villiers", "Chris Gayle"],
    "answer": "Chris Gayle"
    },
    {
    "question": "What is the maximum number of foreign players allowed in an IPL playing XI?",
    "options": ["2", "3", "4", "Unlimited"],
    "answer": "4"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who is the current captain of the Chennai Super Kings (CSK)?",
    "options": ["Ravindra Jadeja", "MS Dhoni", "Suresh Raina", "Ruturaj Gaikwad"],
    "answer": "Ruturaj Gaikwad"
    },
    {
    "question": "What is the name of the stadium that hosted the opening match of IPL 2024?",
    "options": ["Eden Gardens", "M. Chinnaswamy Stadium", "Wankhede Stadium", "M. A. Chidambaram Stadium"],
    "answer": "M. A. Chidambaram Stadium"
    },
    {
    "question": "In which year was the first edition of the Indian Premier League (IPL) held?",
    "options": ["2005", "2007", "2008", "2010"],
    "answer": "2008"
    },
    {
    "question": "What will be the number of matches in IPL 2024?",
    "options": ["60 matches", "74 matches", "84 matches", "90 matches"],
    "answer": "74 matches"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which of the following iconic players remained unsold in the IPL 2022 auction?",
    "options": ["Suresh Raina", "Virat Kohli", "Ravindra Jadeja", "Rohit Sharma"],
    "answer": "Suresh Raina"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who holds the record for the most wickets taken in IPL history?",
    "options": ["Lasith Malinga", "Dwayne Bravo", "Amit Mishra", "Yuzvendra Chahal"],
    "answer": "Yuzvendra Chahal"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which team won the IPL 2023?",
    "options": ["Gujarat Titans", "Mumbai Indians", "Chennai Super Kings", "Royal Challengers Bangalore"],
    "answer": "Chennai Super Kings"
    },
    {
    "question": "What is the maximum number of overs a bowler can bowl in a T20 match?",
    "options": ["2 overs", "3 overs", "4 overs", "5 overs"],
    "answer": "4 overs"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who was the leading run-scorer in IPL 2023?",
    "options": ["Faf du Plessis", "Shubman Gill", "Virat Kohli", "Ruturaj Gaikwad"],
    "answer": "Shubman Gill"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who was the top wicket-taker for the Rajasthan Royals in IPL 2023?",
    "options": ["Trent Boult", "Ravichandran Ashwin", "Yuzvendra Chahal", "Jason Holder"],
    "answer": "Yuzvendra Chahal"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who was the leading run-scorer in IPL 2022?",
    "options": ["Jos Buttler", "KL Rahul", "Faf du Plessis", "Shikhar Dhawan"],
    "answer": "Jos Buttler"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which team was the runner-up in IPL 2023?",
    "options": ["Gujarat Titans", "Mumbai Indians", "Chennai Super Kings", "Royal Challengers Bangalore"],
    "answer": "Gujarat Titans"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who won the Orange Cap in IPL 2023?",
    "options": ["Shubman Gill", "KL Rahul", "Faf du Plessis", "David Warner"],
    "answer": "Shubman Gill"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who won the Purple Cap in IPL 2023?",
    "options": ["Jasprit Bumrah", "Rashid Khan", "Mohammed Shami", "Trent Boult"],
    "answer": "Mohammed Shami"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which cricketer holds the record for the most sixes in the ICC Cricket World Cup 2023?",
    "options": ["David Warner", "Rohit Sharma", "Glenn Maxwell", "Shreyas Iyer"],
    "answer": "Rohit Sharma"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who achieved the highest number of centuries in the ICC Cricket World Cup 2023?",
    "options": ["Rohit Sharma", "Quinton de Kock", "Glenn Maxwell", "Virat Kohli"],
    "answer": "Quinton de Kock"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who among the following did not score a double century in the ICC Cricket World Cup?",
    "options": ["Glenn Maxwell", "Martin Guptill", "David Warner", "Chris Gayle"],
    "answer": "David Warner"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which stadium served as the primary venue for the ICC Cricket World Cup Finale 2023?",
    "options": ["Lord’s Cricket Ground", "Melbourne Cricket Ground", "Eden Gardens", "Narendra Modi Stadium"],
    "answer": "Narendra Modi Stadium"
    },
    {
    "question": "In the 2023 World Cup, which team did India defeat to secure their tenth successive win and advance to the final?",
    "options": ["Australia", "England", "New Zealand", "South Africa"],
    "answer": "New Zealand"
    },
    {
    "question": "In which years did India secure victory in the ICC Cricket World Cup for the two times they won?",
    "options": ["1983 & 2003", "1983 & 2007", "1983 & 2011", "1983 & 2015"],
    "answer": "1983 & 2011"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which wicketkeeper has the highest number of dismissals in the ICC Cricket World Cup 2023?",
    "options": ["KL Rahul", "Tom Latham", "Quinton de Kock", "Josh Inglis"],
    "answer": "Quinton de Kock"
    },
    {
    "question": "What is the term used when a player is bowled out by the first ball they face?",
    "options": ["Golden duck", "Silver duck", "Bronze duck", "Platinum duck"],
    "answer": "Golden duck"
    },
    {
    "question": "What year was the inaugural IPL season?",
    "options": ["2007", "2008", "2009", "2010"],
    "answer": "2008"
    },
    {
    "question": "How many days did the longest recorded Test match last?",
    "options": ["Seven days", "Eight days", "Nine days", "Ten days"],
    "answer": "Nine days"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who is the only batsman to record 400 in a single innings in an international test match?",
    "options": ["Brian Lara", "Sachin Tendulkar", "Ricky Ponting", "Jacques Kallis"],
    "answer": "Brian Lara"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who was the first player to reach 10,000 runs in Test cricket?",
    "options": ["Sachin Tendulkar", "Ricky Ponting", "Sunil Gavaskar", "Brian Lara"],
    "answer": "Sunil Gavaskar"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which teams won the first edition of The 100, in the Men's and Women's events?",
    "options": ["Men's - Manchester Originals, Women's - Oval Invincibles", "Men's - Trent Rockets, Women's  Birmingham Phoenix", "Men's  Southern Brave, Women's  Oval Invincibles", "Men's  Welsh Fire, Women's  London Spirit"],
    "answer": "Men's - Southern Brave, Women's - Oval Invincibles"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who did England beat in the 2019 Cricket World Cup Final?",
    "options": ["Australia", "New Zealand", "India", "South Africa"],
    "answer": "New Zealand"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which legendary cricketer earned the nickname \"The God of Cricket\"?",
    "options": ["Sir Donald Bradman", "Vivian Richards", "Imran Khan", "Sachin Tendulkar"],
    "answer": "Sachin Tendulkar"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which cricketer boasts by some distance the best batting average of all time at 99.94?",
    "options": ["Ricky Ponting", "Brian Lara", "Sachin Tendulkar", "Sir Donald Bradman"],
    "answer": "Sir Donald Bradman"
    },
    {
    "question": "What is the maximum number of overs allowed per bowler in a One Day International (ODI) match?",
    "options": ["10 overs", "15 overs", "20 overs", "25 overs"],
    "answer": "10 overs"
    },
    {
    "question": "In which year was the Decision Review System (DRS) first introduced in international cricket?",
    "options": ["2008", "2009", "2010", "2011"],
    "answer": "2008"
    },
    {
    "question": "India played its first one day international with which country and in which year?",
    "options": ["England 1974", "Australia 1976", "New Zealand 1975", "England 1978"],
    "answer": "England 1974"
    },
    {
    "question": "What is the title of the autography of Major Dhyanchand?",
    "options": ["Goal", "Hockey Days", "Hockey  My Life", "Me & My Hockey"],
    "answer": "Goal"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who has designed the trophy of FIFA Women’s World Cup?",
    "options": ["William Sawaya", "Formiga", "Marta", "Sun Wen"],
    "answer": "William Sawaya"
    },
    {
    "question": "When was the name of National Boxing Association changed to World Boxing Association?",
    "options": ["1958", "1962", "1969", "1970"],
    "answer": "1962"
    },
    {
    "question": "Where are the headquarters of International Paralympic Committee?",
    "options": ["Germany", "Bulgaria", "Spain", "England"],
    "answer": "Germany"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which is the governing body of Cycling sport in the world?",
    "options": ["Cycling Association of the World", "World Cycling Federation", "International Cycling Union", "International Cycling Association"],
    "answer": "International Cycling Union"
    },
    {
    "question": "What is the normal time difference between which both the Summer Olympics and Winter Olympics are held?",
    "options": ["1 Year", "2 Years", "3 Years", "4 Years"],
    "answer": "2 Years"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which are the colors of the rings present in the symbol of the Olympic Games?",
    "options": ["Blue, Yellow, Black, Green, Red", "Blue, Orange, Violet, Green, Red", "Blue, Olive, Purple, Green, Red", "Blue, Black, White, Green, Red"],
    "answer": "Blue, Yellow, Black, Green, Red"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which is the second-largest multi-sport event after the Olympic Games?",
    "options": ["European Games", "Pan American Games", "Asian Games", "Commonwealth Games"],
    "answer": "Asian Games"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which country will host the 2026 Asian Games?",
    "options": ["China", "Japan", "Philippines", "South Korea"],
    "answer": "Japan"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which city hosted Independent India’s first National Games of India?",
    "options": ["Madras", "New Delhi", "Patiala", "Lucknow"],
    "answer": "Lucknow"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who was the champion of the 2015 Cricket World Cup?",
    "options": ["New Zealand", "Australia", "India", "England"],
    "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
    "question": "In which Olympics, Kabaddi was introduced for the first time for promotional purposes as a demonstration sport?",
    "options": ["1933 Olympics", "1934 Olympics", "1935 Olympics", "1936 Olympics"],
    "answer": "1936 Olympics"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which country became the runner-up to the 2018 FIFA Football World Cup?",
    "options": ["England", "Belgium", "Croatia", "France"],
    "answer": "Croatia"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which continent’s governing body of football is CONMEBOL?",
    "options": ["North America", "Europe", "South America", "Africa"],
    "answer": "South America"
    },
    {
    "question": "How many “Grand Slam” tennis tournaments are there at present?",
    "options": ["3", "4", "5", "6"],
    "answer": "4"
    },
    {
    "question": "What is Anthony Amalraj famous for?",
    "options": ["As an Indian squash player", "As an Indian badminton player", "As an Indian table tennis player", "As an Indian tennis player"],
    "answer": "As an Indian table tennis player"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which sport’s competition is known as the “Walker Cup”?",
    "options": ["Tennis", "Golf", "Badminton", "Cricket"],
    "answer": "Golf"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which sport’s traditional form is “Malla-yuddha”?",
    "options": ["Wrestling", "Boxing", "Kabaddi", "Hockey"],
    "answer": "Wrestling"
    },
    {
    "question": "What is the biggest cricket stadium in the world?",
    "options": ["Lord's Cricket Ground (England)", "Eden Gardens (India)", "Sydney Cricket Ground (Australia)", "Narendra Modi Stadium (India)"],
    "answer": "Narendra Modi Stadium (India)"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who holds the record for smashing the most sixes in ODI cricket?",
    "options": ["Chris Gayle (West Indies)", "AB de Villiers (South Africa)", "Shahid Afridi (Pakistan)", "Martin Guptill (New Zealand)"],
    "answer": "Shahid Afridi (Pakistan)"
    },
    {
    "question": "How many players of a team are there on the pitch during a hockey match?",
    "options": ["11", "20", "12", "18"],
    "answer": "11"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which country won the most gold medals at the 2012 London Olympics?",
    "options": ["China", "USA", "Russia", "Japan"],
    "answer": "USA"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who won the inaugural ICC T20 Cricket World Cup in 2007?",
    "options": ["Australia", "South Africa", "India", "England"],
    "answer": "India"
    },
    {
    "question": "What is the top prize in American football's National Football League (NFL)?",
    "options": ["Super Bowl", "Pro Bowl", "National Bowl", "President's Bowl"],
    "answer": "Super Bowl"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which Grand Slam tennis tournament is played on a clay court?",
    "options": ["Australian Open", "French Open", "US Open", "Wimbledon"],
    "answer": "French Open"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which type of football match is the “Merseyside Derby”?",
    "options": ["Liverpool v. Manchester United", "Everton v. Liverpool", "Manchester City v. Liverpool", "Liverpool v. Arsenal"],
    "answer": "Everton v. Liverpool"
    },
    {
    "question": "What is the maximum number of players a rugby team can field during a match?",
    "options": ["11", "15", "12", "18"],
    "answer": "15"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who was the first Indian to become the ICC's No. 1 ODI bowler?",
    "options": ["Kapil Dev", "Ravichandran Ashwin", "Manoj Prabhakar", "Anil Kumble"],
    "answer": "Manoj Prabhakar"
    },
    {
    "question": "What is the major prize in professional golf’s PGA Tour?",
    "options": ["Green Jacket", "Purple Jacket", "Gold Jacket", "Brown Jacket"],
    "answer": "Green Jacket"
    },
    {
    "question": "Pen Holder grip is used in which of the following sports?",
    "options": ["Cricket", "Hockey", "Table Tennis", "Badminton"],
    "answer": "Table Tennis"
    },
    {
    "question": "What is the normal time difference between the Summer Olympics and Winter Olympics?",
    "options": ["1 Year", "2 Years", "3 Years", "4 Years"],
    "answer": "2 Years"
    },
    {
    "question": "What are the colors of the rings present in the symbol of the Olympic Games?",
    "options": ["Blue, Yellow, Black, Green, Red", "Blue, Orange, Violet, Green, Red", "Blue, Olive, Purple, Green, Red", "Blue, Black, White, Green, Red"],
    "answer": "Blue, Yellow, Black, Green, Red"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which country hosted the 2022 Commonwealth Games?",
    "options": ["Ireland", "Canada", "England", "New Zealand"],
    "answer": "England"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which city hosted Independent India's first National Games?",
    "options": ["Madras", "New Delhi", "Patiala", "Lucknow"],
    "answer": "Lucknow"
    },
    {
    "question": "In which Olympics was Kabaddi introduced for promotional purposes as a demonstration sport?",
    "options": ["1933 Olympics", "1934 Olympics", "1935 Olympics", "1936 Olympics"],
    "answer": "1936 Olympics"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which country became the runner-up in the 2014 FIFA Football World Cup?",
    "options": ["Argentina", "Belgium", "Croatia", "France"],
    "answer": "Argentina"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which continent's governing body of football is CONMEBOL?",
    "options": ["North America", "Europe", "South America", "Africa"],
    "answer": "South America"
    },
    {
    "question": "How many 'Grand Slam' tennis tournaments are there at present?",
    "options": ["3", "4", "5", "6"],
    "answer": "4"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which sport's competition is known as the 'Walker Cup'?",
    "options": ["Tennis", "Golf", "Badminton", "Cricket"],
    "answer": "Golf"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which sport's traditional form is 'Malla-yuddha'?",
    "options": ["Wrestling", "Boxing", "Kabaddi", "Hockey"],
    "answer": "Wrestling"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which country has won the Football World Cup the most times?",
    "options": ["Argentina", "Germany", "Brazil", "Italy"],
    "answer": "Brazil"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which country became the first nation to win the Football World Cup?",
    "options": ["Brazil", "Italy", "Germany", "Uruguay"],
    "answer": "Uruguay"
    },
    {
    "question": "Pele, a famous sports personality, is related to which game?",
    "options": ["Cricket", "Basketball", "Football", "Tennis"],
    "answer": "Football"
    },
    {
    "question": "Which place is known as the Mecca of Indian football?",
    "options": ["New Delhi", "Mumbai", "Kolkata", "Bangalore"],
    "answer": "Kolkata"
    },
    {
    "question": "In which year was football included as a competitive game in the Olympics?",
    "options": ["1900", "1904", "1908", "1912"],
    "answer": "1908"
    },
    {
    "question": "Who is the captain of the Indian football team?",
    "options": ["Sunil Chhetri", "Sandesh Jhingan", "Gurpreet Singh Sandhu", "Adil Khan"],
    "answer": "Sunil Chhetri"
    }
]